Ásgeir Berg Matthíasson

asgeirberg@hi.is https://asgeirberg.org

Research interests

I currently run my own research project to develop a conventionalist account of mathematical truth, funded by the Icelandic Research Fund (RANNÍS). It is based on my previous work on the rule-following paradox and the philosophy of mathematics.

As a part of this work, I'm also writing papers on inference, what it is to follow a rule, as well as semantic dispositionalism.

Areas of Specialisation: Philosophy of language, philosophy of mathematics, logic, Wittgenstein, the rule-following paradox

Areas of Competence: Metaphysics, epistemology, history of analytic philosophy.

Current position

2022 — present

Postdoctoral Research Fellow

Institute of Philosophy, University of Iceland

Previous positions

2021 - 2022**Adjunct Lecturer** University of Iceland 2020 - 2021**Sessional Instructor** University of Iceland

2016 — 2019 Early Stage Researcher University of Stirling

Education

Gi

2020 PhD in Philosophy, University of St Andrews and University of Stirling (SASP)

Supervised by Peter Sullivan and Crispin Wright.

2015 M.Litt. in Philosophy, University of St Andrews and University of Stirling (SASP)

2013 M.Sc. in Logic, University of Amsterdam